<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shreyas</title>
    <link>https://Shreyas94.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shreyas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 01:37:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Shreyas94.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas94.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 01:37:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas94.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll add my contact details here sometime in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas94.github.io/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 03:10:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas94.github.io/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a wannabe theoretical computer scientist who occasionally dabbles in non-theoretical aspects of CS. I am also learning to play the violin in the Carnatic style. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about this genre before, here&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful modern rendition of a classic tune to get you started Manavyala</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gentle Introduction to Dynamic Complexity</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas94.github.io/blog/2017-12-18-a-gentle-introduction-to-dynamic-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas94.github.io/blog/2017-12-18-a-gentle-introduction-to-dynamic-complexity/</guid>
      <description>$$ \newcommand{\ang}[1]{\langle #1\rangle} \newcommand{\brackets}[1]{\left( #1\right)} $$
This post is an introductory post and is Part 1 of an n-Part series on Dynamic Complexity, where n is unknown.
Since October this year, I have been working with Prof. Samir Datta on the topic of Dynamic Complexity. We are working on several problems in this subject, which I would like to write about sometime in the near future. So I guess it is only fair that I give an overview of the subject. It would be useful but not necessary to have a grasp of basic logic, circuit complexity and descriptive complexity. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this as intuitive and simple as I can. At the same time I will also loosely state the relevant formal definitions. The presentation is geared towards an audience of CS undergraduates. Others who wish to get a quick introduction might also find this useful. I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit the basic definitions in logic and descriptive complexity for the sake of clarity. The presentation is not suitable for someone who seeks a rigorous formal introduction. Such introductions have been written in several papers and dissertations, in particular Thomas Zeume&amp;rsquo;s thesis on Small Dynamic Complexity Classes. I find it pointless to rehash them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Blog</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas94.github.io/blog/2017-12-17-welcome-to-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas94.github.io/blog/2017-12-17-welcome-to-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>I welcome you to this blog. This is going to be an extremely short post. I have been trying to start a blog for a while and have finally found the time to set it up. Through this blog I hope to share interesting ideas, algorithms, problems and proofs that I come across in CS theory. I am also using this blog as an exercise to constantly improve my ability to communicate complex ideas lucidly. I hope you enjoy it</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>