<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Shreyas</title>
    <link>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Shreyas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 03:26:53 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown for Math - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/markdown-math-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 23:55:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/markdown-math-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is a continuation of Part 1. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it I would encourage you to skim through the first paragraph.
Now that we have dispensed with the initial hurdles of setting up our tools and getting a hang of markdown syntax, it&amp;rsquo;s time to discuss how markdown can prove useful to academics. While I write as someone from a mathematical background, I am sure people from other areas will find this equally useful. I have structured this article as a sequence of sections each devoted to one particular feature that most markdown flavours offer, and I find useful. In particular, both the editors I have described in Part 1 support these features. I also mention some more niche features that certain flavours of markdown offer. I finally discuss ways to publish the content online using static site generators. This can help you publish your content such as lecture notes, documentation, or blogs on the web with very little effort on your part.
Tables The pain of typesetting tables would be familiar to anybody using the table environment in latex. The endless commands, the tabular environment, the necessity to constantly plug in &amp;amp;&amp;rsquo;s to separate cells in a row and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown for Math - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/markdown-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 04:23:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/markdown-math/</guid>
      <description>I am back after a ten month hiatus. While I am keen on continuing my Dynamic Complexity series, in this two post series, I wish to write on a topic of broader interest to people working in mathematical disciplines: The use of markdown for typesetting. This subject is fairly large so I split it into two parts. In part-1, I do not go into math and diagrams, so readers who are expecting math would be disappointed. I&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered in part 2. I think, and I hope you will agree, that it is only fair that I give an introduction to markdown to those who may not have heard of it.
To those who are new to markdown, I welcome you to a beautiful and simple language that will save you tonnes of time, if you invest a very small chunk of it learning markdown. In particular, if you are a student or professor who has to typeset mathematical lecture notes, problem sheets, or even blogs, you will find this useful. Many mathematicians, physicists, and computer scientists do use it in their blogs. This post is for those who haven&amp;rsquo;t discovered markdown yet.
Why Markdown? $\LaTeX$ is an indispensable tool in the mathematical sciences for writing documents containing mathematical notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gentle Introduction to Dynamic Complexity</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/2017-12-18-a-gentle-introduction-to-dynamic-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/2017-12-18-a-gentle-introduction-to-dynamic-complexity/</guid>
      <description>$$ \newcommand{\ang}[1]{\langle #1\rangle} \newcommand{\brackets}[1]{\left( #1\right)} $$
This post is an introductory post and is Part 1 of an n-Part series on Dynamic Complexity, where n is unknown.
Since October this year, I have been working with Prof. Samir Datta on the topic of Dynamic Complexity. We are working on several problems in this subject, which I would like to write about sometime in the near future. So I guess it is only fair that I give an overview of the subject. It would be useful but not necessary to have a grasp of basic logic, circuit complexity and descriptive complexity. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this as intuitive and simple as I can. At the same time I will also loosely state the relevant formal definitions. The presentation is geared towards an audience of CS undergraduates. Others who wish to get a quick introduction might also find this useful. I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit the basic definitions in logic and descriptive complexity for the sake of clarity. The presentation is not suitable for someone who seeks a rigorous formal introduction. Such introductions have been written in several papers and dissertations, in particular Thomas Zeume&amp;rsquo;s thesis on Small Dynamic Complexity Classes. I find it pointless to rehash them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Blog</title>
      <link>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/2017-12-17-welcome-to-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Shreyas4991.github.io/blog/2017-12-17-welcome-to-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>I welcome you to this blog. This is going to be an extremely short post. I have been trying to start a blog for a while and have finally found the time to set it up. Through this blog I hope to share interesting ideas, algorithms, problems and proofs that I come across in CS theory. I am also using this blog as an exercise to constantly improve my ability to communicate complex ideas lucidly. I hope you enjoy it</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>